Tauseef Ibne Mamun

tmamun@mtu.edu +1 (857)-574-9931 https://tm-cv-p.herokuapp.com

407 Shelden Avenue, Apt 9, Houghton, Michigan, 49931

SUMMARY

Graduate student in Applied Cognitive Science and Human Factors at Michigan Technological University with a strong programming background and training in both computer science and psychology. Experience in human factors analysis and executing usability studies mainly in software and rail systems.

EDUCATION

Michigan Technological University | Houghton, MI

Ph.D. Applied Cognitive Science and Human Factors

Expected May 2023

Michigan Technological University | Houghton, MI

MSc. Applied Cognitive Science and Human Factors

2019 - 2021

Ahsanullah University of Science & Technology | Dhaka, Bangladesh

BSc. Computer Science & Engineering

2011 - 2015

EXPERIENCES

Michigan Technological University, Cognitive and Learning Sciences | Houghton, MI

Research Assistant

2019 – Present

Tasks:

- Improving and designing novel explanation methods for AI systems.
- Developing computational models for Explainable Artificial Intelligence (XAI) systems.
- Behavioral analysis of drivers in rail crossings through statistical models and interviews; also determining the usability of new systems in rail crossings.
 - Working/Worked with Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency and Federal Railroad Administration on different research projects.

Mighty Egg Technologies | 600 – 56 Temperance Street Toronto, ON M5H 3V5, Canada

Programmer Analyst

2015 - 2019

Tasks:

- Database Design & API development.
- Web and Mobile App Development.
- Analyzing Client Requirements.
- Software deployment in Amazon Web Service, Digital Ocean, Heroku.

Programming Expertise

Ruby, Python, C, C++, Java, PHP, R, PEBL

Git: GitHub, Bitbucket

CO-CURRICULAR INVOLVEMENT

President (Photography Department) at Notre Dame Nature Study Club
2009 – 2010

 General member at Ahsanullah University of Science & Technology's Computer Science & Engineering Society

 General Secretary at Ahsanullah University of Science & Technology's Computer Science & Engineering Society

Vice President at Ahsanullah University of Science & Technology's Computer Science & Engineering
Society

Vice President at Bangladeshi Student Association at Michigan Technological University
2020 – 2021

INTERESTS

Photography | App Development | Video and Photo Editing